<record xmlns='http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim'><leader>04876ntm a2200277Ii 4500</leader><controlfield tag='001'>991058301963906011</controlfield><controlfield tag='005'>20220506125116.0</controlfield><controlfield tag='008'>220506q16281629enk           000 0 eng d</controlfield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='035'><subfield code='a'>(OCoLC)1314385883h</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='035'><subfield code='a'>(OCoLC)on1314385883h</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='040'><subfield code='a'>HRH</subfield><subfield code='b'>eng</subfield><subfield code='e'>dcrmmss</subfield><subfield code='c'>HRH</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='041'><subfield code='a'>eng</subfield><subfield code='a'>lat</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='049'><subfield code='a'>HRHH</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='9' tag='099'><subfield code='a'>MS 3327, Container 76</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1='0' ind2='0' tag='245'><subfield code='a'>Speeches, petitions, reports, etc. from the Third Parliament of Charles I :</subfield><subfield code='k'>manuscript.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='0' tag='264'><subfield code='a'>England ;</subfield><subfield code='c'>1628-1629</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='300'><subfield code='a'>215 leaves :</subfield><subfield code='b'>paper,</subfield><subfield code='c'>30 x 18 cm</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='506'><subfield code='a'>Unrestricted, for either reading room or classroom use.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'><subfield code='a'>Content list entitled Speeches of King Charles I, etc..., numbered 1-28</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1='0' ind2=' ' tag='505'><subfield code='a'>1. fol. 1r-3v: King Charles I&apos;s speech to the Upper House, 4th May;2. fol. 5r-8r: Petition of both houses to King about suppressing of priests, Jesuits, and recusants;3. fol. 9r-10v: His Majesties&apos; answer;4. fol. 11r-11v: Petition for a fast;5. fol. 13r-17v: Collection of Sir John Eliot&apos;s speeches in the Parliament;6. fol. 19r: Excerpt from Sir Eliot&apos;s speech (?)7. fol.21r-26v: Lord Keeper&apos;s speech in surreplie to the speakers;8. fol. 27r: King&apos;s propositions, fourteen in number;9. fol. 29r: King&apos;s message, delivered by Secretary Cook, 23 January 1628;10. fol. 29r-30v: King&apos;s speech at the Banquetting House, 24 January 1628;11. fol. 31r-32v: Mr. Rowse in Parliament, 27 January 1628;12. fol. 33r-35r: Notes of speeches made at the debates in Parliament concerning the King&apos;s propositions, including those by Mr. Alford, Sir Robert Mansell, Sir Francis Seymour, Sir Peter Hamon, Mr. Prince, Secretary Coke, Sir D. Digges, Mr. Spencer, Sir John Eliot, Sir E. Cooke, Sir Thomas Wentworth, Sir Henry Martin, Mr. Rocton, Sir Robert Phillips, Secretary Hoskings;13. fol. 36r: Censure of Sir Roger Manering Clarke;14. fol. 38r-38v: King&apos;s speech at the dissolution of the Parliament, 10 March 1628;15. fol. 40r-40v: King&apos;s speech to both houses in the Upper House, 17 March 1627;16. fol. 41r-44r: Lord Keeper&apos;s Speech in Parliament, 17 March 1627;17. fol. 44r-48r: Speaker&apos;s speech in Parliament, 17 March 1627;18. fol. 50r-56r: Speeches of Sir Francis Seymour, Sir Thomas Wentworth, Sir Robert Phillips, and Sir Benjamin Rudyers in Parliament, 22 March 1627/8;19. fol. 58r-59v: Sir John Cooke&apos;s speech at the Conference, concerning the petition to the King against recusants, 28 March 162820. fol. 60r-61r: Proceedings at the Council April 4th, and the Duke of Buckingham&apos;s speech to the King;21. fol. 62r-62v: Message from the King to the House of Commons, delivered by Sir John Cooke, 12 April 1628;22. fol. 64r-72v: Speeches of the Speaker and the King, 14 April 1628;23. fol. 74r-74v: Lord Speaker&apos;s speech in Parliament, 28 April 1628;24. fol. 75r: Message from the King to both houses by Secretary Cooke, 5 May 1628;25. fol. 76r-79r: Questions and answers in House of Commons concerning freedoms and liberties, 18 April 1628;26. fol. 80r: Sir Dudley Digges&apos; report of what the Lord Keeper at a conference of both houses declared concerning the Resolution before the Lords, 21 April 1628;27. fol. 82r-84v: Speeches of the Archbishop of Canterbury and Sir Dudley Digges at a conference of both Houses, 25 April 1628;28. fol. 86r-124v: Speeches of the King and others from May-June 1628;29. fol. 126r-138r: The Remonstrance, and the King&apos;s speech, 17 June 1628;30. fol. 139r-142r: Second Remonstrance, prevented by sudden break up on 28 June 1628;31. fol. 144r-215v: The examination and proceedings in the Star Chamber and King&apos;s Bench against the Knights and gentlemen committed to the Tower and other prisons... after the Parliament was dissolved.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='590'><subfield code='a'>MS 3327, Container 76: Unidentified [parchment?] pressmark, L. J. I. 9, later changed to L. J. III; possibly sold at Sotheby&apos;s 28-29 April 1969, as lot 50; acquired by the Ransom Center (R4998) in 1969. Binding: Full brown tanned reversed calfskin over paper boards. Pulled-over caps, tight back over sewing supports, uneven edges (compilation of different sized papers knocked to head).  Three-line blind-tooled border front and back covers, three-line blind-tooled lines at raised bands, gold-tooled red goatskin title label (second spine panel) [re-used?], blind-tooled decorative roll on board edges. Traces of numbers (45, 44) in ink on fore edge. Sewn endbands over core (pink/white thread) head and tail. Endleaf components: front sewn folds (two nested) off-white handmade laid paper making stub, pastedown, remnant of missing endleaf, free endleaf; back sewn folds (two nested) off-white handmade laid paper making stub, pastedown, two free endleaves. Evidence of spine repair at head end.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='7' tag='655'><subfield code='a'>Petitions.</subfield><subfield code='2'>rbgenr</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='7' tag='655'><subfield code='a'>Addresses.</subfield><subfield code='2'>rbgenr</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1='2' ind2=' ' tag='791'><subfield code='a'>Medieval and Early Modern Manuscripts Collection.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='752'><subfield code='a'>England,</subfield><subfield code='e'>producation place.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='994'><subfield code='a'>C0</subfield><subfield code='b'>HRH</subfield></datafield></record>
