<record xmlns='http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim'><leader>07315ntc a2200385Ii 4500</leader><controlfield tag='001'>991058301966006011</controlfield><controlfield tag='005'>20220506121533.0</controlfield><controlfield tag='008'>220506k15491607enk           000 0 eng d</controlfield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='035'><subfield code='a'>(OCoLC)1314385630h</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='035'><subfield code='a'>(OCoLC)on1314385630h</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='040'><subfield code='a'>HRH</subfield><subfield code='b'>eng</subfield><subfield code='e'>dcrmmss</subfield><subfield code='c'>HRH</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='041'><subfield code='a'>dut</subfield><subfield code='a'>fre</subfield><subfield code='a'>ita</subfield><subfield code='a'>lat</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='049'><subfield code='a'>HRHH</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='9' tag='099'><subfield code='a'>MS 3327, Container 55</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1='0' ind2='0' tag='245'><subfield code='a'>Letters, 1549-1607, written to Abraham Ortelius or his nephew Jacobus Colius :</subfield><subfield code='k'>manuscript.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='0' tag='264'><subfield code='a'>London? ; 1549-1607</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='300'><subfield code='a'>44 items:</subfield><subfield code='b'>paper</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'><subfield code='a'>Title devised by cataloger.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'><subfield code='a'>Abraham Ortelius was a cartographer and geographer; Jacobus Colius (1563-1628),  was a London-based merchant.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='506'><subfield code='a'>Unrestricted, for either reading room or classroom use.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1='0' ind2=' ' tag='505'><subfield code='a'>HRC 55.1-5Arias Montano, Benito (1527-1598). Letters, 1576-1596, Rome, Seville, Camp Florido near Seville, Camp Flores near Seville to Abraham Ortelius. 5 items. Written in Latin.HRC 55.6Assonleville, Christophe d&apos;. Letter, 1587 June 12, Antwerp to Abraham Ortelius. 1 item. Written in French.HRC 55.7-8Barbosa, Emanuel. Letters, 1593 September 26 and 1594 December 1, Porto to Abraham Ortelius. 2 items. Written in Latin.HRC 55.9Barvicius, Johannes. Letter, 1578 October 7, to Abraham Ortelius. 1 item. Written in Latin.HRC 55.10Bizzarri, Pietro (b. 1525?). Poem, 1570, to Abraham Ortelius. 1 item. Written in Latin.HRC 55.11Camden, William (1551-1623). Letter, 1577 September 24, London to Abraham Ortelius. 1 item. Written in Latin.HRC 55.12Colius, Jacobus (1563-1628). Letter, 1597 October 18, Rome to Abraham Ortelius. 1 item. Written in Latin.HRC 55.13Danti, Ignazio (1536-1586). Letter, 1580 December 24, Rome to Abraham Ortelius. 1 item. Written in Italian.HRC 55.14Dycchius, Andreas. Letter, 1596 October 25, Venice to Abraham Ortelius. 1 item. Written in Latin.HRC 55.15-16Fabius, Scipio. Letters, 1561 June 16 and 1565 April 14, Bologna to Abraham Ortelius. 2 items. Written in Latin. Scipio Fabius was a physician to whom Ortelius dedicated his second world map.HRC 55.17Hakluyt, Richard (d. 1591). Letter, circa 1590, London to Abraham Ortelius. 1 item. Written in Latin. HRC 55.18La Planche, Adam de. Letter, 1595 October 27, Paris to Abraham Ortelius. 1 item. Written in French.HRC 55.19Magdeburg, Hiob (1518-1595). Letter, 1574 March 8, Lubek [=LuÌ⁸beck] to Abraham Ortelius. 1 item. Written in Latin.HRC 55.20Matal, Jean (1520-1597). Letter, 1575 October 21, Cologne to Abraham Ortelius. 1 item. Written in Latin.HRC 55.21Matal, Jean (1520-1597). Letter, 1580 December 29, Cologne to Abraham Ortelius. 1 item. Written in Latin.HRC 55.22-23Mercator, Gerhard (1512-1594). Letters, 1570 November 22 and 1572 May 9, Duysburg [=Duisburg] to Abraham Ortelius. 2 items. Written in Latin.HRC 55.24Michaelis, Laurentius (16th century). Letter, 1583 September 28 (October 8), Jever to Abraham Ortelius. 1 item. Written in Latin.HRC 55.25Monau, Jacob (1546-1603). Letter, 1579 October 15, Breslau to Abraham Ortelius. 1 item; original seal attached. Written in Latin.HRC 55.26Moravus, Johannes Jonas. Letter, 1590 April 10, Frankfurt to Abraham Ortelius. 1 item. Written in Latin.HRC 55.27Mylius, Arnold (1540-1604). Letter, 1594 December 26, Cologne to Abraham Ortelius. 1 item. Written in Latin.HRC 55.28Occo, Adolf (1524-1606). Letter, 1582 November 15 (or 5), Augsburg to Abraham Ortelius. 1 item. Written in Latin.HRC 55.29-30Orlandi, Cesare, Count (1527-after 1575). Letters, 1572 May 15 and 1574 April 26, Rome to Abraham Ortelius. 2 items. Written in Latin and Italian. HRC 55.31Ortelius, Abraham (1527-1598). Letter, 1590 August 25, Antwerp to Jacobus Colius. 1 item. Written in Latin.HRC 55.32Pigafetta, Filippo (1533-1604). Letter, 1591 July 31, Rome to Abraham Ortelius. 1 item. Written in Latin.HRC 55.33-37Radermacher, Johan (1538-1617). Letters, 1603-1607, Middleburg to Jacobus Colius. 5 items. Written in Latin.HRC 55.38Rogers, Daniel (1538-1590). Letter, 1572 October 20, Windsor to Abraham Ortelius. 1 item. Written in Latin.HRC 55.39Roma, Johan. Letter, 1583 June 25, Augsburg to Abraham Ortelius. 1 item. Written in Latin.HRC 55.40Sadeler, Jan (1550-1600), and Sadeler, Raphael (circa 1560-circa 1632). Letter, 1594 March 28, Munich to Abraham Ortelius. 1 item. Written in Dutch.HRC 55.41Secovius, Nicolaus. Letter, 1579 November 1, Naples to Abraham Ortelius. 1 item. Written in Latin.HRC 55.42Vendville, Jean, Bishop of Tournai (d. 1592). Letter, 1568 June 21, Douay [=Douai] to Abraham Ortelius. 1 item. Written in Latin.HRC 55.43Vivianus, Johannes (d. 1598). Letter, 1594 June 20, Aix-la-Chapelle [=Aachen] to Abraham Ortelius. 1 item; original seal attached. Written in Latin.HRC 55.44Werdenstein, Johann Georg von (1542-1608). Letter, 1596 August 10, Augsburg to Abraham Ortelius. 1 item; also includes letter from Johan Jacques RuÌ⁸eger to Werdenstein. Written in Latin.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='581'><subfield code='a'>Abrahami Ortellii (Geographi Antverpiensis) Et Virorvm Ervditorvm ad Evndem et ad Jacobvm Colivm Ortelianvm (Abrahami Ortelii Sororis filivm) Epistvlae, edited by Jan Hendrik Hessels in 1887, which is the first volume of the collection entitled, Ecclesiae Londino-Batavae Archivvm.Cleaves, David. Abraham Ortelius: Reading an Atlas through Letters. Library Chronicle v.23, no.4 (1993):130-43.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='581'><subfield code='a'>Jan Hendrik Hessels, ed., Abrahami Ortellii (geographi Antverpiensis) et virorvm ervditorvm ad evndem et ad Jacobvm Colivm Ortelianvm (Abrahami Ortelii sororis filivm) epistvlae, Ecclesiae Londino-Batavae Archivum, vol. 1 (Cambridge: University Press, 1887); W. J. C. Moens, Review of Ecclesiae Londino-Batavae Archivum in The English Historical Review (1891): 385-393; David Cleaves, Abraham Ortelius: Reading an Atlas through Letters, Library Chronicle 23, no. 4 (1993): 130-43.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='590'><subfield code='a'>MS 3327, Container 55: Jacobus Colius bequeathed the letters to the Dutch Church in Austin Friars, London; housed in Guildhall Library in 1862; Dr. Otto Fischer; [sold at Sotheby&apos;s, 17-18 June 1968?]; offered in several lots by New York bookseller H. P. Kraus in his Catalogue 124, Monumenta Cartographica; purchased by the Ransom Center in 1972. Bibliography: Jan Hendrik Hessels, ed., Abrahami Ortellii (geographi Antverpiensis) et virorvm ervditorvm ad evndem et ad Jacobvm Colivm Ortelianvm (Abrahami Ortelii sororis filivm) epistvlae, Ecclesiae Londino-Batavae Archivum, vol. 1 (Cambridge: University Press, 1887); W. J. C. Moens, Review of Ecclesiae Londino-Batavae Archivum in The English Historical Review (1891): 385-393; David Cleaves, Abraham Ortelius: Reading an Atlas through Letters, Library Chronicle 23, no. 4 (1993): 130-43. DIDB record: 198 (1); 199 (1); 200 (1); 202 (1); 35811 (124). Unbound letters in polyester sleeves.  See examples of  locked letters, repaired.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='0' tag='650'><subfield code='a'>Cartography.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='7' tag='655'><subfield code='a'>Correspondence.</subfield><subfield code='2'>rbgenr</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='7' tag='655'><subfield code='a'>Seals.</subfield><subfield code='2'>rbgenr</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1='1' ind2=' ' tag='700'><subfield code='a'>Ortelius, Abraham,</subfield><subfield code='e'>addressee.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1='1' ind2=' ' tag='700'><subfield code='a'>Colius, Jacobus,</subfield><subfield code='d'>1563-1628,</subfield><subfield code='e'>addressee.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1='1' ind2=' ' tag='790'><subfield code='a'>Colius, Jacobus,</subfield><subfield code='d'>1563-1628,</subfield><subfield code='e'>former owner.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1='1' ind2=' ' tag='790'><subfield code='a'>Fischer, Otto,</subfield><subfield code='e'>former owner.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1='2' ind2=' ' tag='791'><subfield code='a'>Austin Friars (Church : London, England),</subfield><subfield code='e'>former owner.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1='2' ind2=' ' tag='791'><subfield code='a'>H.P. Kraus (Firm),</subfield><subfield code='e'>seller.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1='2' ind2=' ' tag='791'><subfield code='a'>Medieval and Early Modern Manuscripts Collection.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='994'><subfield code='a'>C0</subfield><subfield code='b'>HRH</subfield></datafield></record>
