<record xmlns='http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim'
><leader
  >07014ctm a2200589Ki 4500</leader
  ><controlfield tag='001'
  >99900468584101852</controlfield
  ><controlfield tag='005'
  >20200520073635.8</controlfield
  ><controlfield tag='008'
  >180301q14301470it p          000 0 lat d</controlfield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='035'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >(OCoLC)1026484794</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='035'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >(OCoLC)on1026484794</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='035'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >(EXLNZ-01ALLIANCE_NETWORK)99324887736001451</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='040'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >ORU</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >eng</subfield
    ><subfield code='e'
    >rda</subfield
    ><subfield code='c'
    >ORU</subfield
    ><subfield code='d'
    >OCLCQ</subfield
    ><subfield code='d'
    >ORU</subfield
    ><subfield code='d'
    >OCLCF</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='041'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >lat</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='049'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >MAIN</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='1' ind2=' ' tag='100'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Cicero, Marcus Tullius,</subfield
    ><subfield code='e'
    >author.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='1' ind2='0' tag='245'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Orationes ;</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >In C. Sallustium Invectiva and Oratio ad Romanos ; In M. Tullium Ciceronem Invectiva.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='0' tag='264'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Italy,</subfield
    ><subfield code='c'
    >between 1430 and 1470?</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='300'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >252 leaves :</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >parchment;</subfield
    ><subfield code='c'
    >230 x 325 mm bound to 240 x 330 mm.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='336'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >text</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >txt</subfield
    ><subfield code='2'
    >rdacontent</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='337'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >unmediated</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >n</subfield
    ><subfield code='2'
    >rdamedia</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='338'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >volume</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >nc</subfield
    ><subfield code='2'
    >rdacarrier</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='561'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Written in book: &quot;preparatoria ad missam opus Johannis van Memmelinghe&quot;, nephew of painter Hans Memling (Edward Sandford Burgess&apos;s notes). Autographed P. S. Kuyl, in same style as van Memmelinghe&apos;s autograph, indicating Memmelinghe gave it to Kuyl (Burgess&apos;s notes). Formerly owned by Edward P. Warren of Boston, Massachusetts. Burgess apparently paid $750. Given by Julia Burgess in memory of her mother.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='583'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Item cataloged from existing description by C. Pierce and J. Fox, and in hand by Erika Milo and Ian Scott, July/August 2018.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='540'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >All requests for permission to quote or publish from manuscripts must be submitted in writing to the Head of Special Collections &amp; University Archives.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='1' ind2=' ' tag='541'
  ><subfield code='c'
    >Donation/Purchase ;</subfield
    ><subfield code='a'
    >Julia Burgess,</subfield
    ><subfield code='d'
    >1935-1942.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='520'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Orations. Publius Cornelius Sulla was implicated along with Catiline for the insurrection at the beginning of 62 BCE. Through the efforts of Cicero he was exonerated from all charges.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Manuscript codex.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Title devised by cataloger.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Collation: 25 quires: 24 consisting of 10 leaves, the last of one. Vertical catchwords on last leaf of each quire. No signatures.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Origin: Italy, early 15th century.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Layout: Single column, 36 long lines, ruled with lead point and stylus.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Script: Humanistic minuscule in brown ink, rubrication at chapter openings and page titles. Inconsistent use of long &apos;s&apos; (initial, medial, and final letter). Short ascenders and descenders.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Decoration: One full page illumination with three-quarter border of interlaced white vines set off by blue, rose, and green, with cherubs, birds, butterfly, and florets. Inside the raised gold initial &apos;Q&apos; is a medallion portrait of Cicero (in blue robe and pink cowl and cap) holding a book. There are scattered clusters of dots of raised gold, outlined in extremely thin penwork. In the lower margin, there is a medallion which held a coat of arms, now obliterated. 37 large initials in gold and white vine against blue, rose, and green, at first lines of orations.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Binding: 19th century parchment, gauffered gilt edges in lattice pattern. Spine title in brown ink: &quot;M. Tullii Ciceronis Opera.&quot; Pink and blue head and tail bands. One paper flyleaf at front and back.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Annotations: Note on free endpaper: &quot;Prof. Clark looked hastily at this MS. He thought it certainly subsequent to 1430 and probably before 1470.&quot;</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Shelfmark: Eugene, OR, Special Collections and University Archives, University of Oregon, MS 048.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='546'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >In Latin.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='0' ind2=' ' tag='505'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >l. 1r M. Tullii Ciceronis de Lege Maniliana Oratio and Quirites incipit feliciter -- l. 7v: M. Tullii Ciceronis pro A. Licinio Poeta Oratio incipit ad iudices -- l. 11r M. Tullii Ciceronis Oratio in Catilinam incipit habita in senatu -- l. 14v M. Tullii Ciceronis in L. Catalina Oratio incipit ad quirites secunda -- l. 21r In Catilinam Invectiva IIII -- l. 24r Crispi Salustii in M. Tul. Ciceronem -- l. 24v M. Tullii Ciceronis Oratio in Crispum Salustin incipit -- l. 26v M. Tullii Ciceronis pro T. Annio Milone Oratio incipit -- l. 36r M. Tullii Ciceronis pro cn. Plancio Oratio ad iudices incipit -- l. 47v M. Tullii Ciceronis pro P. Sylia Oratio ad iudices incipit feliciter -- l. 56v M. Tullii Ciceronis pro A. Cecinna oratio incipit -- l. 68v M. Tullii Ciceronis pro C. Rabirio Posthumo Oratio ad iudices incipit -- l. 72r M. Tullii Ciceronis pro C. Rabirio Perduellione o ratio ad Quirites incipit -- l. 75v M. Tullii Ciceronis oratio pro Roscio Comedo -- l. 81r M. Tullii Ciceronis pro Q. Ligario Oratio ad C. Caesarem incipit -- l. 84r M. Tullii Ciceronis in Vatinium testem Oratio incipit -- l. 89r M. Tullii Ciceronis ad Equites Romanos pridie quam iret in exilium incipit -- l. 92r M. Tullii Ciceronis Oratio ad Qurities in Reditu suo incipit -- l. 95r M. Tullii Ciceronis Oratio ad Senatum post reditum suum incipit -- l. 99r M. Tullii Ciceronis de Provinciis Consularibus Oratio incipit -- l. 106r M. Tullii Ciceronis pro M. Caelio Oratio incipit -- l. 111v M. Tullii Ciceronis de lege Agraria Oratio ad Quirites incipit -- l. 123v M. Tullii Ciceronis de lege Agraria liber primus -- l. 126r M. Tullii Ciceronis de lege Agraria contra P. Rullum liber II incipit -- l. 140r M. Tullii Ciceronis pro M. Marcello Oratio incipit -- l. 143r M. Tullii Ciceronis pro Rege Deiotaro Oratio incipit -- l. 146v M. Tullii Ciceronis pro A. Cluentio Habito Oratio ad iudices incipit -- l. 167r M. Tullii Ciceronis pro L. Flacco ad Iudices Oratio incipit -- l. 177r M. Tullii Ciceronis pro P. Quintio Oratio incipit -- l. 185v M. Tullii Ciceronis oratio pro Domo sua ad Pontifices incipit -- l. 201r M. Tullii Ciceronis pro P. Sextio Oratio incipit -- l. 214v M. Tullii Ciceronis pro L. Cornello Balbo Oratio incipit -- l. 221r M. Tullii Ciceronis pro Sexto Roscio Amerino Oratio incipit -- l. 234v M. Tullii Ciceronis pro L. Murena Oratio incipit -- l. 241r M. Tullii Ciceronis de Responsis aruspicum Oratio incipit.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='506'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >RESTRICTED ORIGINAL. USE DIGITAL COPY ONLY:</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >Use of original only by permission of the rare books curator. Inquiries concerning this item should be directed, in writing, to the Public Services Librarian, Special Collections Department, UO Libraries, or electronically:</subfield
    ><subfield code='u'
    >https://library.uoregon.edu/special-collections/research-assistance.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='0' tag='650'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Manuscripts, Medieval</subfield
    ><subfield code='z'
    >Oregon</subfield
    ><subfield code='z'
    >Eugene.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='7' tag='650'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Manuscripts, Medieval.</subfield
    ><subfield code='2'
    >fast</subfield
    ><subfield code='0'
    >(OCoLC)fst01008422</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='7' tag='651'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Oregon</subfield
    ><subfield code='z'
    >Eugene.</subfield
    ><subfield code='2'
    >fast</subfield
    ><subfield code='0'
    >(OCoLC)fst01205922</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='0' tag='655'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Manuscripts, Latin (medieval and modern).</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='7' tag='655'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Gauffered edges (Binding).</subfield
    ><subfield code='2'
    >rbbin</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='2' ind2=' ' tag='710'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >University of Oregon.</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >Libraries.</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >Special Collections &amp; University Archives.</subfield
    ><subfield code='k'
    >Manuscript.</subfield
    ><subfield code='n'
    >MS 048.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='0' ind2=' ' tag='700'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Pseudo-Cicero,</subfield
    ><subfield code='e'
    >author.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='0' ind2=' ' tag='700'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Pseudo-Sallust,</subfield
    ><subfield code='e'
    >author.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='1' ind2=' ' tag='700'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Burgess, Edward Sandford,</subfield
    ><subfield code='d'
    >1855-1928,</subfield
    ><subfield code='e'
    >former owner.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='1' ind2=' ' tag='700'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Burgess, Julia,</subfield
    ><subfield code='e'
    >former owner.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='851'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Special Collections and University Archives,</subfield
    ><subfield code='c'
    >University of Oregon, Eugene, OR 97403.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='8' ind2=' ' tag='852'
  ><subfield code='8'
    >22330899510001852</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >SpecColl</subfield
    ><subfield code='c'
    >spvaultxxx</subfield
    ><subfield code='h'
    >MS 048</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='994'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >92</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >OCACL</subfield
    ></datafield
  ></record
>