<record xmlns='http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim'
><leader
  >08056ctm a2200613Ki 4500</leader
  ><controlfield tag='001'
  >99900470084801852</controlfield
  ><controlfield tag='005'
  >20200308062223.6</controlfield
  ><controlfield tag='008'
  >180302s1484    be p          000 0 lat d</controlfield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='035'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >(OCoLC)1026501310</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='035'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >(OCoLC)on1026501310</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='035'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >(EXLNZ-01ALLIANCE_NETWORK)99324896105901451</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='040'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >ORU</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >eng</subfield
    ><subfield code='e'
    >rda</subfield
    ><subfield code='c'
    >ORU</subfield
    ><subfield code='d'
    >ORU</subfield
    ><subfield code='d'
    >OCLCQ</subfield
    ><subfield code='d'
    >OCLCA</subfield
    ><subfield code='d'
    >ORU</subfield
    ><subfield code='d'
    >OCLCF</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='041'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >lat</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='049'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >MAIN</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='2' ind2=' ' tag='110'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Catholic Church.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='1' ind2='0' tag='240'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Book of hours</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='1' ind2='0' tag='245'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Horae Beatae Virginis Mariae cum Calendario (Book of Hours with Calendar).</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='0' tag='264'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Flanders,</subfield
    ><subfield code='c'
    >approximately 1484.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='300'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >206 leaves :</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >parchment ;</subfield
    ><subfield code='c'
    >112 x 168 mm bound to 116 x 178 mm.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='336'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >text</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >txt</subfield
    ><subfield code='2'
    >rdacontent</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='337'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >unmediated</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >n</subfield
    ><subfield code='2'
    >rdamedia</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='338'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >volume</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >nc</subfield
    ><subfield code='2'
    >rdacarrier</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='3' ind2=' ' tag='510'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Lackaff, D. Flemish or Dutch? A study of Burgess Ms 38 in the University of Oregon library (Unpublished research paper), 1997.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='3' ind2=' ' tag='510'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Parrott, N. A Flemish Treasure (Unpublished research paper), 1965. Portland, Oregon, Portland State University.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='561'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >The names Petrus Warimont and Franciscus Warimont, 1603, are written on the first flyleaf, with &quot;Donatus est hic liber Anna Elise De Coulons a Reverendissimo P. Warimont...in Homborch anno domini 1603.&quot;  (Possibly De Coulon, a river and region in France?)  The 2nd fly leaf indicates ownership by another Petrus Warimont in 1674.  Thomas Thorp of London obtained it from Kent.  It was offered for sale at Sotheby&apos;s 11/13/1933, Lot 11 (per Jim Marrow, 1985).  Given to the University of Oregon in honor of Irene Hamilton Burgess (wife of Edward Sandford Burgess).</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='583'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Item cataloged from existing description by C. Pierce and J. Fox, and in hand by Erika Milo and Ian Scott, July/August 2018.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='540'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >All requests for permission to quote or publish from manuscripts must be submitted in writing to the Head of Special Collections &amp; University Archives.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='1' ind2=' ' tag='541'
  ><subfield code='c'
    >Donation/Purchase ;</subfield
    ><subfield code='a'
    >Julia Burgess,</subfield
    ><subfield code='d'
    >1935-1942.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Manuscript codex.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Title devised by cataloger.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Collation: Quires of 8 plus 2 new flyleaves in front, 3 in back. No titles or signatures, leaves numbered in pencil 1-206.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Origin: Flanders.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Layout: Single column, 19 lines each. Ruled in lead point or graphite. Some pricking marks visible at the bottom of most pages.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Script: Gothic minuscule in brown ink. First two pages have cursive inscription in Latin dated 1603.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Decoration: Extensively decorated. Illumination is of high quality and originality but shows considerable wear from use.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Decoration: Two double-page illuminations: 1. Large miniature in gold and colors at left side, historiated initial and text at right; broad four-sided borders surrounding both. F. 77v scene of crucifixion, and border with four Evangelist animals, foliage, human figures in each corner, and an angel on the right. F. 78r has historiated letter &apos;C&apos; showing the betrayal of Christ, and a foliage border with a tonsured priest, a monkey, and a bird. 2. F. 133v has interior scene of a woman (in pink gown, black and white headdress, and black cloak; probably the patron of the manuscript) and her patron St. Bernard, both kneeling in prayer before the Virgin and Child. A four-sided foliage border has an angel playing a harp, a bird, an angel with a hunting horn and spear pursuing a unicorn, a Flemish lady in a pink dress and black hennin playing a lute, and another angel. F. 134r has a large initial &apos;I&apos; and a foliage border with a bird and a monk.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Decoration: Three single page illuminations: large historiated or decorated initials in raised gold on blue, with central panel of text and full-page borders of flowers, birds, and acanthus foliage. 1. F. 53r has historiated initial &apos;H&apos; and foliage border with a swan and another bird. 2. F. 92r has initial &apos;H&apos; and border with monkey. 3. F. 163r has initial &apos;I&apos; and foliage border.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Decoration: 18 historiated initials (showing 6 Hours of the Cross and Suffragia, etc.) with half-borders, and 32 large capitals in gold and colors with marginal decorations: delicate brown ink vines and accents with sprays of stylized acanthus foliage, naturalistic fruit and flowers (including columbine, tulips, morning-glories, and myrtle), often inhabited by birds (falcons, pelican, owl, thrush, dove, peacock, hen and chicks, bird-of-paradise, etc.), animals (fox, rabbit, monkey, baby boar, kangaroo, etc.), several grotesques (griffin, unicorn), and insects (butterflies/ moths). Colors mainly raised gold, light pink, several shades of green, light and dark blue, and touches of white, yellow, red, and brown. Smaller blue or raised gold capitals throughout, 8-10 on most pages. Calendar contains two circular numerical charts, each titled with date MCCCCLXXXIIII (1484). Some initials have incised designs on the gold backgrounds (e.g. F. 136v).</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Decoration: Rubrication includes numerals in the Kalendar, full lines, capital letters and names of certain saints, feast days, underlining of select phrases, and corrections.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Binding: Modern conservator&apos;s binding in style of the period, dark brown leather over wood boards, four raised cords, front and back covers blind-tooled with a grid of vertical and horizontal lines. Gilt edges. Flyleaves of heavy modern paper.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Shelfmark: Eugene, OR, Special Collections and University Archives, University of Oregon, MS 038.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='546'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >In Flemish.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='0' ind2=' ' tag='505'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Kalendar ff. 1-12b. The calendar does not include entries for every day of the year, and is approximately half full. Entries in red include St. Agnes, Landoald, Pancras, Boniface, Odulf, Martin, Laurence, Lambert, Remigius and Bavo, Gereon, Willibrord, Lebuin, Nicholas, Thomas, and Steven. St. Donatian was added in a later hand, suggesting the book was not originally made for Bruges usage. Saints such as Agnes, Odulf, Lebuin, and Willibrord point to the use of Utrecht (Lackaff, 1997, p. 3). Names of the months and saints are in a mix of Latin and Dutch. On the versos of January and December are two computation circles, one for finding the Dominical letters in the lunar month of 28 days (f. 1a), and the other for computing the golden number (f. 12r). Each figure includes on its outer, upper right edge the numerals &quot;m cccc lxxx iiij&quot; dating the ms to 1484 (Lackaff, 1997, p. 3) -- Hours of the Blessed Virgin, ff. 13-52. Compline is followed by &apos;Salve Regina&apos; f. 49 -- Seven Penitential Psalms and Litany, ff. 53-76 -- Hours of the Cross, ff. 77-91 -- Hours of the Eternal Wisdom, and Trinity, ff. 92-132v -- Prayers to the Virgin and to St. Bernard and St. Thomas, ff. 133-138 -- Prayers of St. James, St. George, St. Augustin, St. Barbara, St. Sebastian, St. Nicholas, St. Anthony, St. Mary Magdalene, St. Margaret; All Saints and Angels, ff. 148-162v -- Vigelia, Office of the Dead etc., ff. 163-203v (with Lessons) -- Seven Prayers of St. Gregory, ff. 205-206.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='506'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >RESTRICTED ORIGINAL. USE DIGITAL COPY ONLY:</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >Use of original only by permission of the rare books curator. Inquiries concerning this item should be directed, in writing, to the Public Services Librarian, Special Collections Department, UO Libraries, or electronically:</subfield
    ><subfield code='u'
    >https://library.uoregon.edu/special-collections/research-assistance.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='0' tag='650'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Manuscripts, Medieval</subfield
    ><subfield code='z'
    >Oregon</subfield
    ><subfield code='z'
    >Eugene.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='7' tag='650'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Manuscripts, Medieval.</subfield
    ><subfield code='2'
    >fast</subfield
    ><subfield code='0'
    >(OCoLC)fst01008422</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='7' tag='651'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Oregon</subfield
    ><subfield code='z'
    >Eugene.</subfield
    ><subfield code='2'
    >fast</subfield
    ><subfield code='0'
    >(OCoLC)fst01205922</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='0' tag='655'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Manuscripts, Dutch.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='2' ind2=' ' tag='710'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >University of Oregon.</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >Libraries.</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >Special Collections &amp; University Archives.</subfield
    ><subfield code='k'
    >Manuscript.</subfield
    ><subfield code='n'
    >MS 038.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='1' ind2=' ' tag='700'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Burgess, Edward Sandford,</subfield
    ><subfield code='d'
    >1855-1928,</subfield
    ><subfield code='e'
    >former owner.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='1' ind2=' ' tag='700'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Burgess, Julia,</subfield
    ><subfield code='e'
    >former owner.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='851'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Special Collections and University Archives,</subfield
    ><subfield code='c'
    >University of Oregon, Eugene, OR 97403.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='8' ind2=' ' tag='852'
  ><subfield code='8'
    >22329338670001852</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >SpecColl</subfield
    ><subfield code='c'
    >spvault</subfield
    ><subfield code='h'
    >MS 038</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='994'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >92</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >OCACL</subfield
    ></datafield
  ></record
>