<record xmlns='http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim'
><leader
  >09696ctm a2200661Ii 4500</leader
  ><controlfield tag='001'
  >99900470084901852</controlfield
  ><controlfield tag='005'
  >20200115084347.3</controlfield
  ><controlfield tag='008'
  >180302q15331538it p          000 0 lat d</controlfield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='035'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >(OCoLC)1026502037</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='035'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >(OCoLC)on1026502037</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='035'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >(EXLNZ-01ALLIANCE_NETWORK)99324896054701451</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='040'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >ORU</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >eng</subfield
    ><subfield code='e'
    >rda</subfield
    ><subfield code='c'
    >ORU</subfield
    ><subfield code='d'
    >OCLCQ</subfield
    ><subfield code='d'
    >ORU</subfield
    ><subfield code='d'
    >OCLCF</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='041'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >lat</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='049'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >MAIN</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='0' ind2='0' tag='245'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Privilegia et documenta de monasterium S. Zenonis aiorii Veronae spectantia ab anno 883 usque ad annum 1533.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='0' tag='264'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Verona, Italy;</subfield
    ><subfield code='c'
    >between 1533 and 1538 .</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='300'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >76 folios :</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >parchment ;</subfield
    ><subfield code='c'
    >250 x 350 mm</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='336'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >text</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >txt</subfield
    ><subfield code='2'
    >rdacontent</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='337'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >unmediated</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >n</subfield
    ><subfield code='2'
    >rdamedia</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='338'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >volume</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >nc</subfield
    ><subfield code='2'
    >rdacarrier</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='4' ind2=' ' tag='510'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Bond, W., and Faye, C. Supplement to the census of Medieval and Renaissance manuscripts in the United States and Canada,</subfield
    ><subfield code='c'
    >page 433, item 22.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='3' ind2=' ' tag='510'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Gaylin, J. An analysis of &quot;Privilegia et documenta d monasterium S. Zenonis aiorii Veronae spectantia ab anno 883 usque ad annum 1533&quot;. [Unpublished research paper for History 410, Dr. Raymond Birn and Bernard McTigue. Eugene, Oregon: University of Oregon.]</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='561'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Remained at the Monastery of St. Zeno at least until 1588, the last date recorded in the manuscript. Written in pencil on inside front cover: &quot;Verona, XVI c., 71&quot;. Purchased by Sarah Julia Burgess (1870-1942) from L&apos;Art Ancien for the University (per note attached to Gaylin&apos;s paper, author unknown). L&apos;Art Ancien S. A. was a bookseller founded in 1920 in Lugano, Switzerland by Dr Erwin Rosenthal (1889-1981).</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='583'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Item cataloged from existing description by C. Pierce and J. Fox, and in hand by Erika Milo and Ian Scott, July/August 2018.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='540'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >All requests for permission to quote or publish from manuscripts must be submitted in writing to the Head of Special Collections &amp; University Archives.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='541'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Acquired by purchase and donation from Julia Burgess, circa 1935-1924.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='1' ind2=' ' tag='541'
  ><subfield code='c'
    >Donation/Purchase ;</subfield
    ><subfield code='a'
    >Julia Burgess,</subfield
    ><subfield code='d'
    >1935-1942.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='520'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >The Privileges and Donations to the Monastery of St. Zeno the Greater/Elder of Verona pertaining to the period from the year 833 to the year 1533. The list of authorities granting privileges includes rulers such as Otto I (963-973), Henry II (1002-1024), Pope Urban III (1185-1187), rulers of Verona, Dukes of Venice, and Countess Beatrice. Evidence of local historical events and the relationships of these people to the people and policies of Verona. (Gaylin, page 5). Many entries also include the monogram of the privilege grantor (Gaylin, page 6).</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Manuscript codex.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Title devised by cataloger.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Collation: Quires of 10, second to last of 8, last of 6. The original rubricated foliation begins on 1a and ends on folio 53. Foliation in Arabic numerals in brown ink begins on f. 2, and brief marginal notes and underlined sections. Modern pencil foliation begins on first (blank) page.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Origin: Verona, Italy. The Monastery of St. Zeno in Verona was dedicated to St. Zeno, 8th bishop of Verona, 4th c. (Gaylin, 1994, page 2). The monastery was certainly in existence by the reign of Otto I (962-973), who contributed to the church&apos;s completion.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Layout: Main text in one column of 40 lines. Ruled with hard point.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Script: Mainly humanistic minuscule. Inconsistent slope and spacing. Many abbreviations, ligatures, and truncation marks (often omitted). Later script by Cresci in 1560 is better quality. From v. 54 to v. 59 there are letters in various cursive hands in Latin and Italian, dating from April, 1538 to 1588 (Gaylin, 1994, page 3).</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Decoration: One full page illuminated border and simple illuminated initials throughout. Full page is in a highly realistic Renaissance style with trompe l&apos;oeil jewel-like elements and drop-flower large initial &apos;I&apos; and bottom border. Colors are mainly blue, red, black, white, and gold, with green and yellow, and painted gold. The border is framed in gold lines, selectively outlined in black ink and pale yellow. Each corner has rectangular panels of yellow lattice on red, with delicate green vines and white flower sprays. The top border depicts gold ornaments with red jewels, and white pearls, connected by stylized foliage in red and blue with touches of yellow, and a center oval medallion with a crowned white dove radiating yellow light against blue. The left border has green, blue, and yellow foliage and flowers (including blue forget-me-nots) with touches of yellow, on a background of gold or dark red with small yellow dots, with a small area of silver paint at top and bottom. There is a center oval medallion outlined in silver and gold, with a putto executed in subtle blue-on-blue monochrome. The bottom border has a wide panel with a drop-flower border of carnation, rose, forget-me-not, and a white flower, with green stems and leaves, on a gold background; there is also a red and black beetle and an earthworm. In the center of this panel is a coat of arms in red, gold, and blue on a gold shield, surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s red hat and red 12-tasseled cords, on a blue fabric backdrop hanging from 6 nails. The coat of arms is a circular Tuscan shield, with a gold bend sinister (upper left to lower right) on an azure field, and a border gules with a gold cross and 7 gold stars. Bond and Faye (1962., page 433, item 22) attribute the coat of arms to Bishop Bernardo Navagero (1507-1565), a Venetian ambassador; Gaylin (1994, page 10) disagrees because the manuscript was completed well before he became a cardinal in 1561. The right border has the same colors and foliage as the left, with three medallions: the center of a putto holding a book, in monochrome blue-on-blue, the top and bottom with classical figures in monochrome grey on black: the upper a seated armored figure with a Greek helmet and shield (Mars), the lower a standing figure (Artemis), with delicate drapery. Under the top border is a blue banner with the title of the privilege of Charles II in gold capitals. Under this is a large initial I in Red and blue with a white pearl and tiny gold filigree, with a gold drop flower background of strawberries and a white pea flower with green leaves and stems. To the right of the initial are 8 lines of widely spaced capital letters, then a small gold capital A with blue background begins the minuscule text. Initial letter of each entry is a gold capital against a 2 cm square field of red or blue. Three also have gold filigree on the colored background. The last illuminated capital is on v. 30, after which spaces were left but the initials were never added.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Binding: 16th c. Venetian (Gaylin, 1994, page 12), reddish-brown leather on beveled wooden boards, 4 thongs and 4 raised bands on spine, 6 sewing stations, originally with 4 clasps (two at fore-edge, one top and one bottom), one on lower fore-edge now missing. Clasps of brass with a shell motif, on short leather straps. Covers have blind-tooled rectangular lines, and a gold-tooled vine border, with a freestanding floral motif on the outside and inside of each corner. In the center in gold, nude Fortune holding her sail (Gaylin, 1994, page 13) inside a double circle with an abstract border. Paper pastedowns, one blank parchment flyleaf at front.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='500'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Shelfmark: Eugene, OR, Special Collections and University Archives, University of Oregon, MS 030.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='546'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >In Latin.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='0' ind2=' ' tag='505'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >The main Latin text, the last date in which is 1533, continues to r. 54. Rubricated entry headings continue up to f. 49. (Gaylin, 1994, page 3). First entry: privilege of Charles II, Emperor 876-887 (Gaylin, 1994, page 5). In the back, after 14 blank folios, is an entry titled &quot;An index of advances (processus) granted by the favor of the (Maleficiorum) to our monastery of St. Zeno,&quot; dated between Feb. 1555 and May 1587, not included in the letters which follow the main text (Gaylin, 1994, page 4). Note: Gaylin has extensive list of the 59 rubricated entry headings and their translation.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='506'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >RESTRICTED ORIGINAL. USE DIGITAL COPY ONLY:</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >Use of original only by permission of the rare books curator. Inquiries concerning this item should be directed, in writing, to the Public Services Librarian, Special Collections Department, UO Libraries, or electronically:</subfield
    ><subfield code='u'
    >https://library.uoregon.edu/special-collections/research-assistance.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='0' tag='650'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Manuscripts, Medieval</subfield
    ><subfield code='z'
    >Oregon</subfield
    ><subfield code='z'
    >Eugene.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='7' tag='650'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Manuscripts, Medieval.</subfield
    ><subfield code='2'
    >fast</subfield
    ><subfield code='0'
    >(OCoLC)fst01008422</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='7' tag='650'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Theology, Doctrinal.</subfield
    ><subfield code='2'
    >fast</subfield
    ><subfield code='0'
    >(OCoLC)fst01149617</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='7' tag='651'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Oregon</subfield
    ><subfield code='z'
    >Eugene.</subfield
    ><subfield code='2'
    >fast</subfield
    ><subfield code='0'
    >(OCoLC)fst01205922</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='2' ind2='0' tag='610'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >San Zeno Maggiore (Church : Verona, Italy)</subfield
    ><subfield code='x'
    >Doctrines</subfield
    ><subfield code='v'
    >Early works to 1800.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='2' ind2='0' tag='610'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >San Zeno Maggiore (Church : Verona, Italy)</subfield
    ><subfield code='x'
    >History</subfield
    ><subfield code='v'
    >Early works to 1800.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='2' ind2='7' tag='610'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >San Zeno Maggiore (Church : Verona, Italy)</subfield
    ><subfield code='2'
    >fast</subfield
    ><subfield code='0'
    >(OCoLC)fst00574026</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='0' tag='655'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Manuscripts, Latin (medieval and modern).</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='0' tag='655'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Privileges and immunities, Ecclesiastical.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='7' tag='655'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Early works.</subfield
    ><subfield code='2'
    >fast</subfield
    ><subfield code='0'
    >(OCoLC)fst01411636</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2='7' tag='655'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >History.</subfield
    ><subfield code='2'
    >fast</subfield
    ><subfield code='0'
    >(OCoLC)fst01411628</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='2' ind2=' ' tag='710'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >University of Oregon.</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >Libraries.</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >Special Collections &amp; University Archives.</subfield
    ><subfield code='k'
    >Manuscript.</subfield
    ><subfield code='n'
    >MS 030.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='2' ind2=' ' tag='710'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >San Zeno Maggiore (Church : Verona, Italy)</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='1' ind2=' ' tag='700'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Burgess, Edward Sandford,</subfield
    ><subfield code='d'
    >1855-1928,</subfield
    ><subfield code='e'
    >former owner.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='1' ind2=' ' tag='700'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Burgess, Julia,</subfield
    ><subfield code='e'
    >former owner.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='851'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >Special Collections and University Archives,</subfield
    ><subfield code='c'
    >University of Oregon, Eugene, OR 97403.</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1='8' ind2=' ' tag='852'
  ><subfield code='8'
    >22329338700001852</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >SpecColl</subfield
    ><subfield code='c'
    >spvault</subfield
    ><subfield code='h'
    >MS 030</subfield
    ></datafield
  ><datafield ind1=' ' ind2=' ' tag='994'
  ><subfield code='a'
    >92</subfield
    ><subfield code='b'
    >OCACL</subfield
    ></datafield
  ></record
>